<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>4350</number>
    <updateDate>2022-12-29T17:33:53Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2022-12-29T17:33:53Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2022-06-06</introducedDate>
    <congress>117</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>sshr00</systemCode>
        <name>Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2022-06-06T21:20:41Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <relatedBills>
      <item>
        <title>Emergency Infant Formula Act</title>
        <congress>117</congress>
        <number>7875</number>
        <type>HR</type>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2022-05-24</actionDate>
          <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Trade.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
      </item>
    </relatedBills>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2022-06-06</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>sshr00</systemCode>
            <name>Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2022-06-06</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>G000555</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Gillibrand, Kirsten E. [D-NY]</fullName>
        <firstName>Kirsten</firstName>
        <lastName>Gillibrand</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>NY</state>
        <identifiers>
          <bioguideId>G000555</bioguideId>
        </identifiers>
        <middleName>E.</middleName>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Foreign Trade and International Finance</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects/>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Foreign Trade and International Finance</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2022-06-06</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2022-08-29T14:47:22Z</updateDate>
        <text>
          <![CDATA[ <p><strong>Emergency Infant Formula Act</strong></p> <p>This bill addresses the shortage of infant formula in the United States, including by authorizing the President to take certain actions to expedite the importation of such formula.</p> <p>Specifically, the bill authorizes the President to declare through an executive order that a shortage of infant formula exists in the United States. The President may use authorities provided under the Defense Production Act of 1950 in the production of infant formula.</p> <p>Additionally, the President may authorize the importation, distribution, and sale of any covered infant formula if the applicable brand, manufacturer, manufacturing plant, or the specific infant formula product is included in the executive order. <em>Covered infant formula</em> generally refers to any infant formula that is lawfully marketed in the European Union, Canada, Japan, the United Kingdom, or any country the President determines has sufficient health and safety standards with respect to infant formula.</p> <p>The bill exempts imported infant formula from U.S. labeling requirements. The Food and Drug Administration (FDA) must require retailers of imported infant formula to place a label on the product indicating it has not been approved by the FDA.</p> <p>The bill also authorizes the President to reduce or suspend any duties on the importation of covered infant formula or articles used in the production of infant formula.</p> <p>U.S. Customs and Border Protection must give the highest priority and take steps as necessary to expedite the processing of all entries of covered infant formula and articles used in the production of infant formula.</p>]]>
        </text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Emergency Infant Formula Act</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Emergency Infant Formula Act</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Title(s) as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Emergency Infant Formula Act</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in Senate</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IS</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to provide for the expedited and duty-free importation of infant formula that may be lawfully marketed in the European Union, Canada, Japan, or the United Kingdom, and for other purposes.</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in Senate</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IS</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in Senate</type>
        <date>2022-06-06T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-117s4350is/xml/BILLS-117s4350is.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
      <item>
        <date/>
        <formats/>
        <type/>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2022-06-06</actionDate>
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
