<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>589</number>
    <updateDate>2022-12-31T08:01:19Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2022-12-31T08:01:19Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2021-03-04</introducedDate>
    <congress>117</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>ssfi00</systemCode>
        <name>Finance Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2021-03-04T17:43:47Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2021-03-04</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>ssfi00</systemCode>
            <name>Finance Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2021-03-04</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>G000386</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Grassley, Chuck [R-IA]</fullName>
        <firstName>Charles</firstName>
        <lastName>Grassley</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>IA</state>
        <identifiers>
          <bioguideId>G000386</bioguideId>
        </identifiers>
        <middleName>E.</middleName>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Labor and Employment</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Accounting and auditing</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Administrative remedies</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Civil actions and liability</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Corporate finance and management</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Crimes against property</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Disability and paralysis</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Employee benefits and pensions</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Financial services and investments</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Government corporations and government-sponsored enterprises</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Interest, dividends, interest rates</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Pension Benefit Guaranty Corporation</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Labor and Employment</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2021-03-04</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2022-03-01T16:15:00Z</updateDate>
        <text>
          <![CDATA[ <p><b>Chris Allen Multiemployer Pension Recapitalization and Reform Act of 2021</b></p><p>This bill makes various changes with respect to the administration of multiemployer pension plans. </p> <p>Among other provisions, the bill allows qualified multiemployer plans to apply for special partition assistance from the Pension Benefit Guaranty Corporation (PBGC). Partition assistance generally authorizes the PBGC to take financial responsibility for a portion of the liabilities of a plan at risk of insolvency. Subject to certain exceptions and conditions, special partition assistance expands eligibility for partition assistance and does not require plans to repay the amount of assistance received. </p> <p> The bill also revises the PBGC rules for determining whether a plan is insolvent and the procedures for terminating a plan that fails to meet certain standards.</p> <p>Additionally, the bill sets forth the discount rates used to estimate a plan's future benefit payment obligations, which affect an employer's minimum contribution to the plan. It also establishes a stable funding status and an unrestricted funding status and revises the criteria for plans that are in endangered, critical, and critical and declining statuses.</p> <p>Finally, the bill establishes rules for new composite plans. Composite plans provide annuity benefits to plan participants, establish fixed contributions from employers, and require realignment measures if the plan's projected funded ratio falls below 120%. A composite plan's projected funded ratio is the actuarial projection of the plan's assets compared to liabilities as of the first plan day of the 15th plan year following a given plan year.</p>]]>
        </text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Chris Allen Multiemployer Pension Recapitalization and Reform Act of 2021</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Chris Allen Multiemployer Pension Recapitalization and Reform Act of 2021</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Title(s) as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Chris Allen Multiemployer Pension Recapitalization and Reform Act of 2021</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in Senate</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IS</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 and the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 to reform the treatment of multiemployer plans, to ensure the ability of the Pension Benefit Guaranty Corporation to provide guaranteed benefits of retirees, and for other purposes.</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in Senate</type>
        <date>2021-03-04T05:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-117s589is/xml/BILLS-117s589is.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
      <item>
        <date/>
        <formats/>
        <type/>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2021-03-04</actionDate>
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
