<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>2225</number>
    <updateDate>2022-12-30T13:18:11Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2022-12-30T13:18:11Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2021-06-24</introducedDate>
    <congress>117</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>ssga00</systemCode>
        <name>Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2021-06-24T17:26:36Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2021-06-24</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>ssga00</systemCode>
            <name>Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2021-06-24</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>R000595</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Rubio, Marco [R-FL]</fullName>
        <firstName>Marco</firstName>
        <lastName>Rubio</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>FL</state>
        <identifiers>
          <bioguideId>R000595</bioguideId>
        </identifiers>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Government Operations and Politics</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects/>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Government Operations and Politics</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2021-06-24</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2022-03-28T19:00:24Z</updateDate>
        <text>
          <![CDATA[ <p><b>Federal Skills Act</b></p> <p>This bill directs the Office of Personnel Management (OPM) to review and revise all job classification and qualification standards for positions in the competitive service, as necessary. </p> <p>A federal agency may prescribe a minimum requirement with respect to education for a position in the competitive service only if a minimum qualification with respect to education is legally required to perform the duties of a comparable position in the state or locality where those duties are to be performed.</p> <p>The OPM shall work with each agency to ensure that, for a position in the competitive service, the agency assesses an applicant for employment in a manner that does not rely solely on the education of the applicant to determine the extent to which the applicant possesses relevant knowledge, skills, competencies, and abilities for the position.</p> <p>In assessing an applicant for employment</p> <ul> <li> an agency may not rely solely on the self-evaluation of the stated abilities of the applicant; and</li> <li>the applicant shall fulfill other assessment standards in order to be certified for consideration, as established by the Chief Human Capital Officer of the applicable agency (or an equivalent official).</li> </ul>]]>
        </text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Federal Skills Act</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Federal Skills Act</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Title(s) as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Federal Skills Act</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in Senate</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IS</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to require the Director of the Office of Personnel Management to revise job classification and qualification standards for positions in the competitive service regarding educational requirements for those positions, and for other purposes.</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in Senate</type>
        <date>2021-06-24T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-117s2225is/xml/BILLS-117s2225is.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
      <item>
        <date/>
        <formats/>
        <type/>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2021-06-24</actionDate>
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
