<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>5830</number>
    <updateDate>2022-12-30T08:03:40Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2022-12-30T08:03:40Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>House</originChamber>
    <type>HR</type>
    <introducedDate>2021-11-03</introducedDate>
    <congress>117</congress>
    <constitutionalAuthorityStatementText>
      <![CDATA[<pre>[Congressional Record Volume 167, Number 193 (Wednesday, November 3, 2021)][House]From the Congressional Record Online through the Government Publishing Office [<a href="https://www.gpo.gov">www.gpo.gov</a>]By Mr. HOYER:H.R. 5830.Congress has the power to enact this legislation pursuantto the following:The principal constitutional authority for this legislationis clause 1 of section 8 of article 1 of the Constitution(the spending power) provides: ``The Congress shall have thePower . . . to pay the Debts and provide for the commonDefence and general Welfare of the United States . . .''In addition, clause 3 of section 8 of article 1 of theConstitution provides: ``To regulate Commerce with foreignNations, and among the several States, and with the IndianTribes;''In addition, clause 18 of section 8 of article 1 of theConstitution, which provides: ``To make all Laws which shallbe necessary and proper for carrying into Execution theforegoing Powers, and all other Powers vested by thisConstitution in the Government of the United States, or inany Department or Officer thereof.''Together, these specific constitutional provisionsestablish the congressional power of the purse, grantingCongress the authority to appropriate funds, to determinetheir purpose, amount, and period of availability, and to setforth terms and conditions governing their use.[Page H6179]</pre>]]>
    </constitutionalAuthorityStatementText>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>hsfa00</systemCode>
        <name>Foreign Affairs Committee</name>
        <chamber>House</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2021-11-03T16:01:05Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <relatedBills>
      <item>
        <title>AMAZON21 Act</title>
        <congress>117</congress>
        <number>5019</number>
        <type>S</type>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2022-09-29</actionDate>
          <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
      </item>
    </relatedBills>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2021-11-03</actionDate>
        <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>H11100</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>hsfa00</systemCode>
            <name>Foreign Affairs Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2021-11-03</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>Intro-H</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2021-11-03</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>1000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>H000874</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Rep. Hoyer, Steny H. [D-MD-5]</fullName>
        <firstName>STENY</firstName>
        <lastName>HOYER</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>MD</state>
        <identifiers>
          <bioguideId>H000874</bioguideId>
        </identifiers>
        <middleName>H.</middleName>
        <district>5</district>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>International Affairs</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects/>
      <policyArea>
        <name>International Affairs</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2021-11-03</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in House</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2022-07-15T18:20:06Z</updateDate>
        <text>
          <![CDATA[ <p><strong>America Mitigating and Achieving Zero-emissions Originating from Nature for the 21st Century Act or the AMAZON21 Act</strong></p> <p>This bill establishes programs to support efforts in developing countries to address climate change.</p> <p>The Department of State must establish the International Terrestrial Carbon Sequestration Program to make results-based payments to eligible projects in developing countries that reduce emissions and enhance carbon sequestration from forests and other ecosystems. Eligible projects include those where the primary purpose is to (1) reduce deforestation and restore forests to support enhanced carbon sequestration; or (2) preserve other territorial ecosystems, such as wetlands, within the host country. The bill also imposes other requirements on project eligibility, including requirements relating to transparency pertaining to the use of the received payments and the host country's standards of governance and respect for the rule of law. </p> <p>The bill also requires the U.S. Agency for International Development to conduct a program to provide resources and technical assistance to developing countries to (1) conserve, manage, and restore carbon sinks, such as forests; and (2) support nature-based carbon sequestration. A project eligible for such assistance must be located in a country that meets certain criteria, such as a country that permits the sale of carbon credits to voluntary and carbon compliance markets.</p>]]>
        </text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>AMAZON21 Act</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>AMAZON21 Act</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Title(s) as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>AMAZON21 Act</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in House</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IH</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Title(s) as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>America Mitigating and Achieving Zero-emissions Originating from Nature for the 21st Century Act</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in House</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IH</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>To establish an international terrestrial carbon sequestration program and provide international technical assistance for carbon market development, and for other purposes.</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in House</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IH</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in House</type>
        <date>2021-11-03T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-117hr5830ih/xml/BILLS-117hr5830ih.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
      <item>
        <date/>
        <formats/>
        <type/>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2021-11-03</actionDate>
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
