<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>4855</number>
    <updateDate>2022-12-29T13:03:33Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2022-12-29T13:03:33Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2022-09-14</introducedDate>
    <congress>117</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>sscm00</systemCode>
        <name>Commerce, Science, and Transportation Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2022-09-14T21:49:28Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2022-09-14</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>sscm00</systemCode>
            <name>Commerce, Science, and Transportation Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2022-09-14</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>W000437</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Wicker, Roger F. [R-MS]</fullName>
        <firstName>Roger</firstName>
        <lastName>Wicker</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>MS</state>
        <identifiers>
          <bioguideId>W000437</bioguideId>
        </identifiers>
        <middleName>F.</middleName>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Sports and Recreation</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects/>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Sports and Recreation</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2022-09-14</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2022-11-03T16:32:38Z</updateDate>
        <text>
          <![CDATA[ <p><strong>Collegiate Athlete Compensation Rights Act</strong></p> <p>This bill addresses the rights of student athletes and issues of transparency and accountability regarding student athlete name, image, and likeness (NIL) agreements.</p> <p>Specifically, an athletic association, conference, or institution must permit a student athlete or a group of student athletes to </p> <ul> <li> market, or earn compensation for the value of, their NIL; and </li> <li> obtain or retain a certified agent for any matter or activity relating to such compensation.</li> </ul> <p>A third party may not use the NIL of a group to sell or promote any product or service without obtaining the written consent from each member of the group for that purpose.</p> <p>The Federal Trade Commission (FTC) must make available specified educational resources for student athletes with respect to financial and contract literacy and earning compensation for the commercial use of the student athlete's NIL.</p> <p>The bill sets forth prohibitions on activities of institutions, boosters, and third parties, including a prohibition on institutions, athletic associations, or conferences entering into NIL agreements with student athletes. The bill limits transfer penalties and prohibits incentives intended to induce the student athlete to enroll in, maintain enrollment in, or transfer to a particular institution.</p> <p>The FTC must establish an Office of Sport.</p> <p>The Government Accountability Office must report to Congress on the health, safety, and education needs of student athletes.</p>]]>
        </text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Collegiate Athlete Compensation Rights Act</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Collegiate Athlete Compensation Rights Act</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Title(s) as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Collegiate Athlete Compensation Rights Act</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in Senate</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IS</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to protect the rights of student athletes and to provide for transparency and accountability with respect to student athlete name, image, and likeness agreements, and for other purposes.</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in Senate</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IS</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in Senate</type>
        <date>2022-09-14T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-117s4855is/xml/BILLS-117s4855is.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
      <item>
        <date/>
        <formats/>
        <type/>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2022-09-14</actionDate>
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
