<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>4276</number>
    <updateDate>2022-12-29T16:48:35Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2022-12-29T16:48:35Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2022-05-19</introducedDate>
    <congress>117</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>ssva00</systemCode>
        <name>Veterans' Affairs Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2022-05-19T19:25:44Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2022-05-19</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>ssva00</systemCode>
            <name>Veterans' Affairs Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2022-05-19</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>M001111</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Murray, Patty [D-WA]</fullName>
        <firstName>Patty</firstName>
        <lastName>Murray</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>WA</state>
        <identifiers>
          <bioguideId>M001111</bioguideId>
        </identifiers>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <cosponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>B001236</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Boozman, John [R-AR]</fullName>
        <firstName>John</firstName>
        <lastName>Boozman</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>AR</state>
        <identifiers>
          <bioguideId>B001236</bioguideId>
        </identifiers>
        <sponsorshipDate>2022-06-08</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>False</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
    </cosponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Armed Forces and National Security</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects/>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Armed Forces and National Security</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2022-05-19</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2022-06-08T18:23:31Z</updateDate>
        <text>
          <![CDATA[ <p><strong>Helping Heroes Act of 2022</strong></p> <p>This bill implements programs and procedures related to the provision of support services for veterans and their families.</p> <p>First, the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) must place at least one Family Coordinator at each of its medical centers and ensure adequate staffing and resources at each such medical center so the coordinators are able to carry out their duties. Family Coordinators must, among other duties, assess the needs of the families of veterans using evidence-based strategies and refer veterans to support resources.</p> <p>The VA must also establish the Family Support Program to provide and coordinate the provision of supportive services to veterans who have a service-connected disability rated at 70% or more and eligible children (i.e., individuals who are under 18 years of age and are wards, children, stepchildren, grandchildren, or siblings of the eligible veteran).</p> <p>Next, the VA must coordinate with the Department of Education to award competitive grants to local educational agencies to better meet academic, social, emotional, and mental health needs of students whose parent or guardian previously served in the Armed Forces (including reserve components) or the National Guard. </p> <p>The VA must include information regarding supportive services available in the transition assistance curriculum for members of the Armed Forces who are being separated from active duty (and their families).</p> <p>Finally, the VA must conduct an annual survey of disabled veterans and their families to identify and better understand the needs of such persons.</p>]]>
        </text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Helping Heroes Act of 2022</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Helping Heroes Act of 2022</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Title(s) as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Helping Heroes Act of 2022</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in Senate</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IS</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to improve services provided by the Department of Veterans Affairs for veteran families, and for other purposes.</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in Senate</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IS</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in Senate</type>
        <date>2022-05-19T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-117s4276is/xml/BILLS-117s4276is.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
      <item>
        <date/>
        <formats/>
        <type/>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2022-05-19</actionDate>
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
