<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>3558</number>
    <updateDate>2022-12-30T04:48:38Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2022-12-30T04:48:38Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2022-02-02</introducedDate>
    <congress>117</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>ssfr00</systemCode>
        <name>Foreign Relations Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2022-02-02T19:20:54Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <relatedBills>
      <item>
        <title>Values in Arms Export Act of 2022</title>
        <congress>117</congress>
        <number>7367</number>
        <type>HR</type>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2022-04-01</actionDate>
          <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committees on Intelligence (Permanent Select), and Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Identical bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
      </item>
    </relatedBills>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2022-02-02</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>ssfr00</systemCode>
            <name>Foreign Relations Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2022-02-02</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>M001111</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Murray, Patty [D-WA]</fullName>
        <firstName>Patty</firstName>
        <lastName>Murray</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>WA</state>
        <identifiers>
          <bioguideId>M001111</bioguideId>
        </identifiers>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>International Affairs</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects/>
      <policyArea>
        <name>International Affairs</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2022-02-02</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2022-09-13T13:05:17Z</updateDate>
        <text>
          <![CDATA[ <p><strong>Values in Arms Export Act of 2022</strong></p> <p>This bill restricts transferring defense articles and services to countries that violate human rights, imposes such restrictions on Saudi Arabia and the United Arab Emirates (UAE), and addresses related issues.</p> <p>The bill establishes the Human Rights and Law of War Oversight Board. The board's duties shall include (1) reviewing countries that receive U.S. defense articles for strict adherence to human rights and the law of armed conflict principles, and (2) ensuring that such principles are appropriately considered in arms transfers.</p> <p>The President, the Department of State, the Department of Defense, the board, or Congress may designate a country (except for certain exempted countries such as NATO member countries) as a country of concern. Such a designation shall last for three years, during which the country shall be barred from receiving the defense articles that led to the designation. </p> <p>The bill also imposes additional restrictions on a designated country that fails to improve its adherence to human rights principles. The Department of the Treasury must impose sanctions on the appropriate government officials of a country subject to such additional restrictions. </p> <p>The bill designates Saudi Arabia and the UAE as countries of concern. </p> <p>Before certain defense articles transfers, the President must provide Congress an assessment of the risk of the defense articles being used to violate human rights. </p> <p>The bill also requires various government agencies to monitor and report information concerning human rights violations involving U.S. defense articles.</p>]]>
        </text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Values in Arms Export Act of 2022</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Values in Arms Export Act of 2022</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to amend the Arms Export Control Act to provide for better monitoring and verification of the use of defense articles and defense services by countries of concern, and for other purposes.</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in Senate</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IS</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Title(s) as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Values in Arms Export Act of 2022</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in Senate</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IS</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in Senate</type>
        <date>2022-02-02T05:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-117s3558is/xml/BILLS-117s3558is.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
      <item>
        <date/>
        <formats/>
        <type/>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2022-02-02</actionDate>
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
