<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>5330</number>
    <updateDate>2022-12-30T11:18:32Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2022-12-30T11:18:32Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>House</originChamber>
    <type>HR</type>
    <introducedDate>2021-09-22</introducedDate>
    <congress>117</congress>
    <constitutionalAuthorityStatementText>
      <![CDATA[<pre>[Congressional Record Volume 167, Number 164 (Wednesday, September 22, 2021)][House]From the Congressional Record Online through the Government Publishing Office [<a href="https://www.gpo.gov">www.gpo.gov</a>]By Mr. CRENSHAW:H.R. 5330.Congress has the power to enact this legislation pursuantto the following:Article I, Section 8: ``The Congress shall have Power Tolay and collect Taxes, Duties, Imposts and Excises, to paythe Debts and provide for the common Defense and generalWelfare of the United States; but all Duties, Imposts andExcises shall be uniform throughout the United States; Toborrow Money on the credit of the United States; To regulateCommerce with foreign Nations, and among the several states,and with the Indian Tribes; To establish an uniform Rule ofNaturalization, and uniform Laws on the subject ofBankruptcies throughout the United States; To coin Money,regulate the Value thereof, and of foreign Coin, and fix theStandard of Weights and Measures; To provide for thePunishment of counterfeiting the Securities and current Coinof the United States; To establish Post Offices and postRoads; To promote the Progress of Science and useful Arts, bysecuring for limited Times to Authors and Inventors theexclusive Right to their respective Writings and Discoveries;To constitute Tribunals inferior to the supreme Court; Todefine and punish Piracies and Felonies committed on the highSeas, and Offences against the Law of Nations; To declareWar, grant Letters of Marque and Reprisal, and make Rulesconcerning Captures on Land and Water; To raise and supportArmies, but no Appropriation of Money to that Use shall befor a longer Term than two Years; To provide and maintain aNavy; To make Rules for the Government and Regulation of theland and naval Forces; To provide for calling forth theMilitia to execute the Laws of the Union, suppressInsurrections and repel Invasions; To provide for organizing,arming, and disciplining, the Militia, and for governing suchPart of them as may be employed in the Service of the UnitedStates, reserving to the States respectively, the Appointmentof the Officers, and the Authority of training the Militiaaccording to the discipline prescribed by Congress; Toexercise exclusive Legislation in all Cases whatsoever, oversuch District (not exceeding ten Miles square) as may, byCession of particular States, and the Acceptance of Congress,become the Seat of the Government of the United States, andto exercise like Authority over all Places purchased by theConsent of the Legislature of the State in which the Sameshall be, for the Erection of Forts, Magazines, Arsenals,dock-Yards, and other needful Buildings;--And To make allLaws which shall be necessary and proper for carrying intoExecution the foregoing Powers, and all other Powers vestedby this Constitution in the Government of the United States,or in any Department or Officer thereof.''[Page H5091]</pre>]]>
    </constitutionalAuthorityStatementText>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>hsgo00</systemCode>
        <name>Oversight and Reform Committee</name>
        <chamber>House</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2021-09-22T14:01:45Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <relatedBills>
      <item>
        <title>National Treasures Act of 2021</title>
        <congress>117</congress>
        <number>2862</number>
        <type>S</type>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2021-09-27</actionDate>
          <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
      </item>
    </relatedBills>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2021-09-22</actionDate>
        <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Reform.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>H11100</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>hsgo00</systemCode>
            <name>Oversight and Reform Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2021-09-22</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>Intro-H</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2021-09-22</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>1000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>C001120</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Rep. Crenshaw, Dan [R-TX-2]</fullName>
        <firstName>Dan</firstName>
        <lastName>Crenshaw</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>TX</state>
        <identifiers>
          <bioguideId>C001120</bioguideId>
        </identifiers>
        <district>2</district>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <cosponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>B001291</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Rep. Babin, Brian [R-TX-36]</fullName>
        <firstName>Brian</firstName>
        <lastName>Babin</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>TX</state>
        <identifiers>
          <bioguideId>B001291</bioguideId>
        </identifiers>
        <district>36</district>
        <sponsorshipDate>2021-09-29</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>False</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>D000626</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Rep. Davidson, Warren [R-OH-8]</fullName>
        <firstName>Warren</firstName>
        <lastName>Davidson</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>OH</state>
        <identifiers>
          <bioguideId>D000626</bioguideId>
        </identifiers>
        <district>8</district>
        <sponsorshipDate>2021-09-30</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>False</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>C001115</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Rep. Cloud, Michael [R-TX-27]</fullName>
        <firstName>Michael</firstName>
        <lastName>Cloud</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>TX</state>
        <identifiers>
          <bioguideId>C001115</bioguideId>
        </identifiers>
        <district>27</district>
        <sponsorshipDate>2021-10-08</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>False</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>B000825</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Rep. Boebert, Lauren [R-CO-3]</fullName>
        <firstName>Lauren</firstName>
        <lastName>Boebert</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>CO</state>
        <identifiers>
          <bioguideId>B000825</bioguideId>
        </identifiers>
        <district>3</district>
        <sponsorshipDate>2021-10-19</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>False</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>D000032</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Rep. Donalds, Byron [R-FL-19]</fullName>
        <firstName>Byron</firstName>
        <lastName>Donalds</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>FL</state>
        <identifiers>
          <bioguideId>D000032</bioguideId>
        </identifiers>
        <district>19</district>
        <sponsorshipDate>2021-11-01</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>False</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
    </cosponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Crime and Law Enforcement</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Government Operations and Politics</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Crime and Law Enforcement</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2021-09-22</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in House</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2022-03-31T16:35:40Z</updateDate>
        <text>
          <![CDATA[ <p><strong>National Treasures Act of 2021</strong></p> <p>This bill prohibits the National Archives and Records Administration from including content warnings alongside items associated with the founding fathers of the United States.</p> <p><em>Content warning</em> is defined as any message preceding or attached to the document labeling it as dangerous, harmful, anachronistic, or any other terms implying harm associated with the documents; disparaging the documents; assuming malicious intent on the part of the authors; or discouraging potential readers from reading the documents.</p> <p><em>Founding father </em>means any individual who signed the Declaration of Independence, served as an officer in the Revolutionary War, attended the Second Continental Congress, attended the Constitutional Convention, or was granted a charter for one of the original 13 colonies of the United States.</p>]]>
        </text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>National Treasures Act of 2021</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>National Treasures Act of 2021</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>To amend title 44 of the United States Code to prohibit the National Archives and Records Administration from including content warnings alongside founding documents of the United States.</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in House</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IH</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Title(s) as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>National Treasures Act of 2021</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in House</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IH</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in House</type>
        <date>2021-09-22T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-117hr5330ih/xml/BILLS-117hr5330ih.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
      <item>
        <date/>
        <formats/>
        <type/>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2021-09-22</actionDate>
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Reform.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
