<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>39</number>
    <updateDate>2022-12-16T14:09:04Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2022-12-16T14:09:04Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2021-01-25</introducedDate>
    <congress>117</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>ssfi00</systemCode>
        <name>Finance Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2021-01-25T22:21:49Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2021-01-25</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>ssfi00</systemCode>
            <name>Finance Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2021-01-25</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>I000024</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Inhofe, James M. [R-OK]</fullName>
        <firstName>Jim</firstName>
        <lastName>Inhofe</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>OK</state>
        <identifiers>
          <bioguideId>I000024</bioguideId>
        </identifiers>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Foreign Trade and International Finance</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Alternative dispute resolution, mediation, arbitration</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Consumer affairs</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Government information and archives</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Intellectual property</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Licensing and registrations</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Manufacturing</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Retail and wholesale trades</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Technology transfer and commercialization</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Telephone and wireless communication</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Trade restrictions</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Foreign Trade and International Finance</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2021-01-25</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2021-06-29T20:10:32Z</updateDate>
        <text>
          <![CDATA[ <p><b>Protecting American Innovation and Development Act of 2021</b></p> <p>This bill authorizes import controls against certain foreign persons that infringe patents belonging to a U.S. person that are essential to a wireless communications standard. </p> <p>Specifically, the Department of Commerce must create a list of foreign entities that are citizens or nationals of a country of concern and that engage in the unlicensed use (i.e., infringement) of such essential wireless communications patents. A <i>country of concern</i> is a country wherein the persistent infringement of these patents poses a threat to (1) U.S. wireless communications research and development infrastructure, and (2) U.S. national security.</p> <p>Any foreign entity on this list, as well as specified persons that raise a national security concern with respect to wireless communications technology, may be subject to import controls (for example, a foreign entity may be required to post a bond before importing into the United States any goods that potentially infringe the wireless patent in question).</p> <p>Commerce must also establish a watch list of foreign entities from a country of concern that (1) are selling in the United States a product claiming to comply with a wireless standard, and (2) have not obtained a license (or taken certain actions to obtain that license) for patents essential to that wireless standard.</p> <p>An entity on either list may petition Commerce to be removed from that list on the basis that the conditions that led to its inclusion no longer exist. </p>]]>
        </text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Protecting American Innovation and Development Act of 2021</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Protecting American Innovation and Development Act of 2021</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Title(s) as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Protecting American Innovation and Development Act of 2021</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in Senate</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IS</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to ensure the continued strength and leadership of the United States in the research and development of key technologies for future wireless telecommunications standards and infrastructure by providing additional authority for sanctions against certain foreign entities that pose a threat to national security, and for other purposes.</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in Senate</type>
        <date>2021-01-25T05:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-117s39is/xml/BILLS-117s39is.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
      <item>
        <date/>
        <formats/>
        <type/>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2021-01-25</actionDate>
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
