<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>7623</number>
    <updateDate>2022-12-29T23:18:21Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2022-12-29T23:18:21Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>House</originChamber>
    <type>HR</type>
    <introducedDate>2022-04-28</introducedDate>
    <congress>117</congress>
    <constitutionalAuthorityStatementText>
      <![CDATA[<pre>[Congressional Record Volume 168, Number 70 (Thursday, April 28, 2022)][House]From the Congressional Record Online through the Government Publishing Office [<a href="https://www.gpo.gov">www.gpo.gov</a>]By Mr. DAVIDSON:H.R. 7623.Congress has the power to enact this legislation pursuantto the following:Congress has the authority to enact the ``Financial CrimesEnforcement Network Improvements Act'' under the Constitutionof the United States, including the following provisions: (l)Article I, section 5 (``Each House may determine the Rules ofits Proceedings''); (2) Article I, section 8 (``Power To . .. provide for the common Defence and general Welfare of theUnited States''); (3) Article I, section 8 (``Power To . . .make all Laws which shall be necessary and proper forcarrying into Execution the forgoing Powers, and all otherPowers vested by this Constitution in the Government of theUnited States or in any Department or Officer thereof'') as alaw necessary and proper for carrying into execution thePresident's powers under Article II to nominate, appoint, andfaithfully execute the laws, and the provision for executivedepartments, including the Treasury required by Article I,section 9; (4) Article IV, section 3 (``Power to . . . makeall needful Rules and Regulations respecting the . . .Property belonging to the United States''); and (5) theFirst, Fourth, Fifth, Ninth, and Tenth Amendments to theConstitution, protecting the civil liberties and privacyguaranteed to the people.[Page H4609]</pre>]]>
    </constitutionalAuthorityStatementText>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>hsba00</systemCode>
        <name>Financial Services Committee</name>
        <chamber>House</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2022-04-28T14:01:10Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2022-04-28</actionDate>
        <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>H11100</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>hsba00</systemCode>
            <name>Financial Services Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2022-04-28</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>Intro-H</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2022-04-28</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>1000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>D000626</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Rep. Davidson, Warren [R-OH-8]</fullName>
        <firstName>Warren</firstName>
        <lastName>Davidson</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>OH</state>
        <identifiers>
          <bioguideId>D000626</bioguideId>
        </identifiers>
        <district>8</district>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Finance and Financial Sector</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects/>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Finance and Financial Sector</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2022-04-28</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in House</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2022-09-29T12:53:48Z</updateDate>
        <text>
          <![CDATA[ <p><strong>Financial Crimes Enforcement Network Improvements Act </strong></p> <p>This bill makes several organizational changes to the Financial Crimes Enforcement Network (FinCEN). </p> <p>First, the director of FinCEN must be appointed by the President with the advice and consent of the Senate. (Currently, the director is appointed by the Secretary of the Treasury.) </p> <p>The bill also establishes an Office of Audit and Investigations within FinCEN. The office must prioritize audits and investigations that protect the civil liberties and privacy of citizens. The bill also provides for a Civil Liberties Protection Officer to oversee compliance with all guidelines relating to civil liberties and privacy. </p> <p>Further, the bill imposes additional requirements on the rulemaking process for FinCEN, including by limiting the delegation authorities of the Secretary of the Treasury to make findings and exercise authority to certify, delay, or waive certain rulemaking activities. FinCEN is also required to conduct additional outreach to small businesses prior to a rulemaking. </p> <p>Finally, FinCEN must disclose certain controlling documents regarding the implementation of specified laws and must report to Congress any unlawful FinCEN activity and corrective action taken. </p>]]>
        </text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Financial Crimes Enforcement Network Improvements Act</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Financial Crimes Enforcement Network Improvements Act</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Title(s) as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Financial Crimes Enforcement Network Improvements Act</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in House</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IH</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>To increase the effectiveness and accountability of the Financial Crimes Enforcement Network of the Department of the Treasury and to protect the freedom and privacy of Americans, and for other purposes.</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in House</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IH</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in House</type>
        <date>2022-04-28T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-117hr7623ih/xml/BILLS-117hr7623ih.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
      <item>
        <date/>
        <formats/>
        <type/>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2022-04-28</actionDate>
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
