<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>2031</number>
    <updateDate>2022-12-30T13:03:13Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2022-12-30T13:03:13Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2021-06-10</introducedDate>
    <congress>117</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>sscm00</systemCode>
        <name>Commerce, Science, and Transportation Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2021-06-10T19:39:12Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2021-06-10</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>sscm00</systemCode>
            <name>Commerce, Science, and Transportation Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2021-06-10</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>W000437</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Wicker, Roger F. [R-MS]</fullName>
        <firstName>Roger</firstName>
        <lastName>Wicker</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>MS</state>
        <identifiers>
          <bioguideId>W000437</bioguideId>
        </identifiers>
        <middleName>F.</middleName>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Science, Technology, Communications</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Competition and antitrust</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Computers and information technology</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Consumer affairs</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Government studies and investigations</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Internet and video services</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Internet, web applications, social media</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Right of privacy</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Science, Technology, Communications</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2021-06-10</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2022-04-08T13:37:22Z</updateDate>
        <text>
          <![CDATA[ <p><strong>Promoting Rights and Online Speech Protections to Ensure Every Consumer is Heard Act or the PRO-SPEECH Act</strong></p> <p>This bill prohibits internet platforms from restricting access to content and engaging in discriminatory or anticompetitive conduct. An <em>internet platform</em> is an entity that owns or operates an app store, a cloud computing service, an operating system, a search engine, or a social media company.</p> <p>The bill prohibits large internet platforms (those with at least 100 million global users or $500 million in annual revenue) from blocking a user's access to lawful content, applications, services, or devices, or impairing a user's access to lawful internet traffic based on content, application, service, or use of device. This prohibition does not apply if (1) a user's access interferes with a large internet platform's functionality or poses privacy or security risks, or (2) a large internet platform publicly proclaims to be the publisher of the relevant content, application, or service. Further, large internet platforms must publicly disclose policies, terms of service, and other designated information regarding the purchase or use of its products or services.</p> <p>Internet platforms may not discriminate against a user or entity based on racial, sexual, religious, ethnic, or political affiliation grounds. Internet platforms also may not engage in unfair competition (e.g., blocking a competitor's access to an internet platform). The Federal Trade Commission (FTC) may determine whether an action constitutes unfair competition.</p> <p>The FTC shall enforce the bill's provisions through a complaint-driven investigative process.</p> <p>The bill also preempts state laws that conflict with its provisions.</p>]]>
        </text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>PRO-SPEECH Act</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>PRO-SPEECH Act</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Title(s) as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>PRO-SPEECH Act</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in Senate</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IS</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Title(s) as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Promoting Rights and Online Speech Protections to Ensure Every Consumer is Heard Act</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in Senate</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IS</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to preserve access to lawful content and prevent discrimination and unfair methods of competition on the internet, and for other purposes.</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in Senate</type>
        <date>2021-06-10T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-117s2031is/xml/BILLS-117s2031is.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
      <item>
        <date/>
        <formats/>
        <type/>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2021-06-10</actionDate>
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
