<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>4752</number>
    <updateDate>2022-12-29T19:18:38Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2022-12-29T19:18:38Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2022-08-03</introducedDate>
    <congress>117</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>sseg00</systemCode>
        <name>Energy and Natural Resources Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2022-08-03T17:04:05Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2022-08-03</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>sseg00</systemCode>
            <name>Energy and Natural Resources Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2022-08-03</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>W000779</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Wyden, Ron [D-OR]</fullName>
        <firstName>Ron</firstName>
        <lastName>Wyden</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>OR</state>
        <identifiers>
          <bioguideId>W000779</bioguideId>
        </identifiers>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <cosponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>M001176</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Merkley, Jeff [D-OR]</fullName>
        <firstName>Jeff</firstName>
        <lastName>Merkley</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>OR</state>
        <identifiers>
          <bioguideId>M001176</bioguideId>
        </identifiers>
        <sponsorshipDate>2022-08-07</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>False</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
    </cosponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Public Lands and Natural Resources</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects/>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Public Lands and Natural Resources</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2022-08-03</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2022-12-06T22:46:16Z</updateDate>
        <text>
          <![CDATA[ <p><b>Malheur Community Empowerment for the Owyhee Act</b></p> <p>This bill addresses various public land concerns in Malheur County in Oregon.</p> <p>The bill directs the Department of the Interior to prepare a programmatic environmental impact statement for certain federal land in the county. Interior shall develop plans for areas that are ecologically degraded or most at risk of being ecologically degraded. Interior shall establish the Malheur Community Empowerment for Owyhee Group, which shall, among other things, use such statement to review projects proposed to the Bureau of Land Management by group members, ranchers holding grazing permits on the federal land, or other members of the public. </p> <p>The bill also</p> <ul> <li>establishes a network to monitor such land, </li> <li>designates 1,133,481 acres of federal lands in the county as wilderness and components of the National Wilderness Preservation System, </li> <li>designates a 14.7-mile segment of Owyhee River as a recreational river, </li> <li> establishes improvements for certain loop roads, </li> <li>requires separate feasibility studies concerning Owyhee Reservoir, </li> <li>requires improvements to existing Oregon State Parks and private camps on the shore of the Reservoir,</li> <li>establishes a dude ranch at Birch Creek,</li> <li>requires a feasibility study on a specified rails-to-trails project,</li> <li>requires a feasibility study on marketing communities or portions of the county as the Gateway to the Oregon Owyhee,</li> <li>requires a determination of the use and conditions under which the Jordan Valley Airstrip may be used to support firefighting, </li> <li>establishes the Native Seed Center as the primary federal native seed repository in the Western States, and </li> <li>requires that land be taken into trust for the benefit of the Burns Paiute Tribe.</li> </ul>]]>
        </text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Malheur Community Empowerment for the Owyhee Act</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Malheur Community Empowerment for the Owyhee Act</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Title(s) as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Malheur Community Empowerment for the Owyhee Act</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in Senate</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IS</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to require the Secretary of the Interior to prepare a programmatic environmental impact statement allowing for adaptive management of certain Federal land in Malheur County, Oregon, and for other purposes.</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in Senate</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IS</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in Senate</type>
        <date>2022-08-03T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-117s4752is/xml/BILLS-117s4752is.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
      <item>
        <date/>
        <formats/>
        <type/>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2022-08-03</actionDate>
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
